Michael Obi

[(512)-799-7531 | M michael.u.obi1@gmail.com | In LinkedIn | GitHub

Passionate and solution-driven Software Developer based in Austin, TX. Designed and developed web applications using a variety of technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, and Python. Hands-on experience in fron-end and back-end development with a strong focus on responsive design and user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: HTML/CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | C | PHP | C# | MySQL | Python
- Frameworks: React | Redux | jQuery | Bootstrap | SASS | Node.js | Flask | Next.js | Tailwind.css | Framer-Motion | Three.js | SCSS | Express
- Developer Tools: Visual Studio Code | Visual Studio | Git | Azure | AWS | Oracle VM | Vite

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

Arctex Inc.

Jun. 2024 - Aug. 2024

Austin, TX

- Worked with other software developers at Arctex to create and deploy their new 3D Company Website and their AI FormHelper Chrome extension.
- Played a major role in revamping their company website and creating their form helper application as a front-end developer using various libraries and frameworks such as HTML, Tailwind.css, Three.js, React, Express, Node.js and JavaScript.

Line Server Chipotle Oct. 2018 - Apr. 2019

Austin, TX

Worked on the line at Chipotle Restaurant to satisfy customer needs and communicate with customer concerns.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science

University of Texas at San Antonio

Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2023

San Antonio, TX

- Major in Computer Science
- Cumulative GPA: 3.25

CERTIFICATIONS

- FCC Front-End Development Certification: Completed various Front End Development projects and trials in FreeCodeCamp (02/2024)
- PLTW Certification of Achievement: Passed my exam to become PLTW (Project Lead the Way) certified in Engineering Design (05/2017)